<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Insurtent</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Insurtent (Blog)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 01:30:57 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>History of Insurance</title>
      <link>/blog/history-of-insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 23:45:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/history-of-insurance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-insurance&#34; &gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#a-brief-history-of-insurance&#34;&gt;
        ##
    &lt;/a&gt;
    A Brief History of Insurance
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The origins of the insurance business can be traced back to ancient times, when people used various methods to spread and reduce risks. One of the earliest examples of a written insurance policy was found on an ancient Babylonian monument with the code of King Hammurabi carved into it. The code stipulated that a debtor did not have to pay back their loans if some personal catastrophe made it impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In medieval Europe, the guild system emerged, with members paying into a pool that covered their losses in case of fire, theft, disability or death. This was a form of group coverage that encouraged more people to take up trades and increase the production and trade of goods and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the 17th century, as maritime trade expanded, merchants and shipowners sought ways to protect their investments from the perils of the sea. They formed mutual associations and secured multiple investors to share the risks of each voyage. This gave rise to marine insurance, which was formalized by Edward Lloyd&amp;rsquo;s coffee house in London, where underwriters met to offer coverage for ships and cargoes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Great Fire of London in 1666, which destroyed thousands of buildings and homes, prompted the development of fire insurance. Nicholas Barbon opened an office to insure buildings in 1667, and later founded the first fire insurance company in England. Fire insurance companies employed their own fire brigades to prevent or minimize losses from fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life insurance also emerged in the 17th century, initially as a way to provide funds for burials and support for widows and orphans. The first life insurance policies were taken out in the early 18th century by members of the clergy and wealthy merchants³. The invention of mortality tables, which helped predict longevity and calculate premiums, made life insurance more widespread and affordable in the 19th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The insurance industry in America was influenced by the developments in Europe, but also had its own innovations and challenges. The first American insurance company was organized by Benjamin Franklin in 1752 as the Philadelphia Contributionship. The first life insurance company in the American colonies was the Presbyterian Ministers’ Fund, organized in 1759. By 1820 there were 17 stock life insurance companies in the state of New York alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late 19th century, scandals and shady practices rocked the young insurance industry, leading to public outcry and regulatory reforms. The National Association of Insurance Commissioners (NAIC) was formed in 1871 to coordinate state regulation and promote uniform standards. The insurance industry also faced new risks and opportunities with the advent of automobiles, airplanes, radio, television, and other technologies in the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the insurance industry is a global and diverse sector that offers protection and financial security for individuals, businesses, and society as a whole. It covers a wide range of risks, such as health, property, liability, disability, natural disasters, terrorism, cyberattacks, and more. It also plays an important role in providing long-term finance for both the public and private sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
